Register of the Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- VOENNYI PREDSTAVITEL' VERKHOVNAGO PRAVITELIA PRI SOIUZNYKH PRAVITEL'STVAKH I SOUIZNOM VERKHOVNOM KOMANDOVANII, 1919-1920 (Boxes 78-85)
  - (Group I, File 220)
    - Leaflets, printed copies
      - "Prikaz Glavnokomanduiushchago V.S.IU.R.,", May 20 April 29, June 26, 1920 (Folder 21)
      - "Slushaite russkie liudi! Za chto my boremsia?" (Folder 22)
      - "U novago vozhdia antibol'shevistskoi Rossii,", undated (Folder 23)
      - "Vozzvanie Nachal'nika Povstancheskago Otriada Grishina,", June 24, 1920 (Folder 24)
    - Newspaper, Voennyi Golos, No. 138-142, September printed copies, 23-27 (Folder 25)
  - (Group I, File 221)
    - Russian Military Agent in Great Britain, Lieut.-Gen. N. Ermolov
      - Correspondence
        - Military Agency in Great Britain and Gen. D. SHcherbachev, Russian Military Agent in Paris. Includes correspondence of Russian Ambassadors to London, K. Nabokov and E. Sablin; material re British involvement in supplying White Armies, correspondence of British officials, Sir Samuel Hoare and Prof. D. Gardner... reports re conversations with Winston Churchill, activities of British Foreign Office, Cabinet and Parliament; also includes correspondence in transit from Military Agent in Paris to Gens. IUdenich, Kolchak and Denikin, November 1918-October 1919 (Box 85, Folder 1-5)
        - Bicherakhov, Maj.-Gen. L., bona fides and miscellaneous material, typescript, October 1918-March 1919 (Folder 6)
        - Business correspondence, Special Military Mission in Great Britain, includes "Instructions," typescript, June-August 1919 (Folder 7)
      - Financial report, expenditures of Military Agency in Great Britain, typescript, November 1-June 1, 1919 (Folder 8)
      - Intelligence reports, typescript, 1919
        - British military intelligence re Red Army and IUdenich front, April-November (Folder 9)
        - Russian Military Agent in Denmark, mostly re Germany and Scandinavia, July (Folder 10)
          Available on microfilm reel 106
      - List of Russian military personnel abroad, typescript, June, 1919 (Folder 11)
      - Summaries, British press, typescript, March 1919 (Folder 12)
  - (Group I, File 237)
    - Correspondence
      - Ermolov, Lieut.-Gen. N., Russian Military Agent in Great Britain
        - Incoming
          - Hermonius, Lieut.-Gen. E. to Beliaev, Col., telegram, May 22, 1920 (Box 85, Folder 13)
          - Poradelov, Col., January 29-February 4, 1920 (Folder 14)
        - Outgoing, Sablin, E. Copy of decoded telegram from Maj.-Gen. D. Pototskii, January 3, 1920 (Folder 15)
      - Shcherbachev, Gen. D., Voennyi Predstavitel' Russkikh Armii pri Soiuznykh Pravitel'stvakh
        - Incoming
          - Ermolov, Lieut.-Gen. N., Includes decoded telegrams and business correspondence, January 17-April 21, 1920 (Folder 16)
          - Gerua, Maj.-Gen. G., February 9-19, March 27, 1920 (Folder 17)
          - Kholmsen, Lieut.-Gen. I., January 1-6, March 3-25, 1920 (Folder 18)
          - Sablin, E. Includes decoded telegrams, and copies of correspodence with Sir Archibald Sinclair, January 9-21, 1920, January 16-May 6, 1920 (Folder 19)
        - Outgoing, Shcherbachev, Gen. D. to Lieut.-Gen. N. Ermolov, February 10, 1920 (Folder 20)
      - Reports
        - Author unknown, "Svodka svedenii, poluchennykh voennoi agenturoi v Velikobritanii putem neglasnoi sekretnoi razvedki," Nos. 1-2, typescript, January 1, 1920 (Folder 21)
        - Ermolov, Lieut.-Gen. N., "Obzor britanskoi pechati," typescript, February 29-March 28, 1920 (Folder 22)
        - Gardner, D. to Maj.-Gen. D. Shcherbachev, typescript, January 8, 20, 23, 27, 1920 (Folder 23)
- UPRAVLENIE ZAVEDUIUSHCHAGO ORGANIZATSIEI RUSSKOI AVIATSII VO FRANTSII, 1918-1919 (Boxes 86-87)
  Miscellaneous material re training of Russian aviators in France and the French aviation squadron in Siberia. Files 197-201.
  - (Group I, File 197)
    - Correspondence, office, mostly with Col. Ducimetière, chargé de l'organisation, de l'instruction et de l'entrainement du personnel d'aviation russe, désigné à être envoyé en Orient, typescript copies, January-June 1919 (Box 86, Folder 1-5)
  - (Group I, File 198)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, office, mostly re personnel, including transfer of military personnel to White Armies, No. 422-699, typescript, June-Sept, 1919 (Box 86, Folder 6-8)
      Folder 6 available on microfilm reel 106; folders 7-8 on reel 107
  - (Group I, File 199)
    - Correspondence. General. Includes material re supply; personnel training in France and their transfer to White Armies, typescript, 1919 (Box 86, Folder 9-13)
      Available on microfilm reel 107
    - Lists of personnel, typescript
      - Russian aviation in France, May 1919 (Folder 14)
      - Aviators joining forces of Lieu-tGen. A. Denikin, April 1919 (Folder 15)
      - Officers and enlisted men, Red Air Force, December 1918 (Folder 16)
      - Russian aviation in England, May 1919 (Folder 17)
    - Report, Bouazin (?), Lieut.-Col., Commander, Aeronautics, French Military Mission in Siberia re air power of White forces in Siberia and the West, typescript of Russian translation from French, undated (Folder 18)
    - Clippings, French press, miscellaneous re Civil War, July 1-15, 1919 (Folder 19)
  - (Group I, File 200)
    - Miscellaneous material related to personnel. Includes correspondence and military service records, typescript and handwritten, January-June 1919 (Box 87, Folder 1-5)
    - Lists of personnel, May-July, 1919 (Folder 6)
      Available on microfilm reel 108
  - (Group I, File 201)
    - Personnel records, Russian officers in training in France. Includes Russian officers, mechanics and other personnel of First Regiment of French Foreign Legion assigned to mission of Gen. Janen? in Siberia; officers transferred to Armies of Danube and Gen. N. IUdenich, typescript and handwritten, 1919 (Box 87, Folder 7-13)
- GLAVNOUPOLNOMOCHENNYI GLAVNOKOMANDUIUSHCHAGO VOORUZHENNYMI SILAMI IUGA ROSSII (V.S.IU.R.) PO VOENNYM I VOENNO-MORSKIM DELAM V PARIZHE, 1919-1922 (Boxes 88-95)
  Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen and Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller with Russian military agents and others. Includes material re Russian army and army pesonnel in exile; emigre organizations, including Russian Red Cross and Natsional'nyi TSentr; situation in the Far East and Maritime Provinces; intelligence reports re situation in the Soviet Union and Soviet activity in Europe; transcripts of Soviet radio broadcasts. Files 202-217.
  - (Group I, File 202)
    - Correspondence
      - R.S.F.S.R., Rev. Voen. Sovet Respubl. Upravl. zagran. voen. agent. No. 291/45 to Voenagentu R.S.F.S.R. pri Posol'stve v Germanii, secret copy, November 10, 1922 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Vrangel', Baron P. to Gen. Pelle, Haut Commissaire de la République Française en Orient, Constantinople, typescript, December 19, 1921 (Folder 2)
    - Intelligence reports, typescript
      - Bulgaria. Miscellaneous material re mistreatment of Russian military refugees, includes letter of Baron P. Vrangel', September 1922 (Folder 3)
        Available on microfilm reel 109
      - Estonia, Latvia and Poland: their armed forces, July 1922 (Folder 4)
      - Kuban, "Pis'ma s Rodiny. Poluchennyia kazakami Kubanskoi kazachiei divizii,", 1922 (Folder 5)
      - Germany, re refugee administration of League of Nations, undated (Folder 6)
      - Soviet Union
        - General condition, condition of army and fleet, May, June, September 1922 (Folder 7)
        - Siberia. Includes Armies of the Far East, Vladivostok, Also Orders No. 46 (April 20, 1922) and 48 (April 24, 1922) of the Commandant of the Fort of Vladivostok and Order No. 204 of the Amur Provisional Government, April 24, 1922, May 1922 (Folder 8)
      - Turkestan, "Krizis vostochnoi politiki Sovetov i sobytiia v Turkestane,", September 1922 (Folder 9)
      - Ukraine, "Svedeniia po ukrainskomu voprosu,", July, September, October 1922 (Folder 10)
    - Informatsionnaia gruppa "D i L," Belgrade, Bulletin No. 23, 26, typescript, undated (Folder 11)
    - Peace treaty between U.S.S.R. and Latvia, Russian text, typescript, undated (Folder 12)
    - Press, typescript
      - France
        - Miscelaneous excerpts, August-September 1922 (Folder 13)
        - Reactions of Russian military administration to French press. Includes "Memorandum du Conseil Russe," sent to Le Matin with covering letter from Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, printed copy, March 27, 1922 (Folder 14)
      - "Obzor sovetskoi pressy,", August 1-15, 1922 (Folder 15)
    - Russkoe Informatsionnoe Biuro, typescript. Bulletin No. 4-8, No. 9, 12-13, September 3, 4-5, No.15, September 15, July 31-August 1 (Folder 16)
  - (Group I, File 203)
    - Correspondence of Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen with Russian Military Agents, includes typescript and handwritten material unless otherwise indicated
      - CHertkov, Lieut.-Gen. G., Russian Military Agent in Constantinople
        - General, includes letters to Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, December 10, 1921-January 23, 1922 (Box 88, Folder 17)
        - Secret reports re political and military situation in Turkey (Anatolia) and the Middle East. Includes maps and eyewitness accounts, typescript
          - December 21, 1921-June 21,1922 (Folder 18)
          - June 21-November 28, 1922 (Folder 19)
      - Den, Capt. D., Russian Military and Naval Agent in Italy, miscellaneous, January 4-December 13, 1922 (Folder 20)
      - Gerua, Lieut.-Gen. A., Russian Military Agent in Rumania. Includes correspondence with Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, A. Kartashev and others, typescript, October 22, 1919-26 December 1922 (Folder 21)
      - Kandaurov, Col., Russian Military Agent in Sweden and Norway, miscellaneous, January 13-March 30, 1922 (Folder 22)
      - Lampe, Col. A. von, Russian Military Representative of the Commander-in-Chief of the Russian Army in Hungary, miscellaneous, June 3, 1922 (Folder 23)
      - Poliakov, Col., Russian Military Agent in Greece to Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, miscellaneous, March 10, 1922 (Folder 24)
      - Pototskii, Major-Gen. D., Russian Military Agent in Serbia. Includes reports re condition and employment of military refugees and other miscellaneous material, typescript, handwritten and printed, January December 1921-March 1922 (Folder 25)
      - Pustoshvin?, Capt., Russian Mission in the Hague, miscellaneous, February 26, 1921-July 6, 1922 (Folder 26)
      - Viazmitinov, Lieut.-Gen. A., Russian Military Agent in Bulgaria. Includes copy of letter to Bulgarian Minister of War, January 2-April 1, 1922 (Folder 27)
  - (Group I, File 204)
    - Correspondence
      - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. D., Russian Military Agent in Denmark and Lieut. Gen. I. KHolmnsen, Representative of the Commander-in-Chief in Paris and Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, Chief-of-Staff, Russian Army, typescript, Jan 5, 1921-December 30, 1922 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Gartman, Maj.-Gen. E., Russian Military Agent in Great Britain and Lieut.- Gen. I. KHolmnsen, typescript, January 23-December 6, 1922 (Folder 2)
      - Military Representative in the U.S., typescript, April 30-July 16, 1922 (Folder 3)
    - Reports. Includes material re political situation in Scandinavia; activity of Soviet agents and official delegations (especially trade) in Scandinavia and Germany; political situation in the Soviet Union and the Ukraine; condition of Soviet Army; organization of Soviet intelligence apparatus; Soviet secret documents and correspondence published by German authorities, typescript, 1922
      - December 16, 1921-February 1 (Folder 4)
      - February 15-April 12 (Folder 5)
      - April 16-24 (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 110
      - May 3-June 4 (Folder 7)
      - July 22-August 5 (Folder 8)
      - August 2-August 29 (Folder 9)
      - October 10-November 1 (Folder 10)
      - November 7-December 16 (Folder 11)
  - (Group I, File 205)
    - Courts-martial. Miscellaneous material, typescript and handwritten
      - Jansen, Capt. D., includes eyewitness accounts of Russian prisoners in Austrian prisoner of war camps, April 1919-April 1920 (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - Lifshits, Ensign G. and Klenov, Ensign V., includes correspondence with French authorities, 1917-December 1919 (Folder 13-14)
      - Godnev, Lieut. I., includes correspondence of Baron P. Vrangel' with V. Kuz'min-Karavaev re courts-martial and executions in Gallipoli, September-November 1921 (Folder 15)
  - (Group I, File 206)
    - Leontiev, Maj.-Gen. M., Russian Military Agent in Czechoslovakia
      - Correspondence, typescript unless otherwise indicated, 1922
        - CHertkov, Lieut.-Gen. G., Military Agent in Constantinople, March 2 (Box 90, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 111
        - Il'in, S., September 6-October 22 (Folder 2)
        - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., January 21-29 (Folder 3)
        - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., Chief-of-Staff, Russian Army. Includes clippings from Czech press, typescript and handwritten, December 1921-October 1922 (Folder 4-6)
        - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen. D., Russian Military Agent in Serbia, April 16 (Folder 7)
        - SHatilov, Gen. P., Chief-of-Staff, Russian Army, January 9-March 14 (Folder 8)
      - Summaries of periodical press, mimeograph copies, 1922
        - December 15, 1921-January 30, 1922 (Folder 9)
        - February 25-April 20 (Folder 10)
        - April 21-September 12 (Folder 11)
  - (Group I, File 207)
    - Correspondence
      - General, typescript and handwritten, October 1919-December 22,1921 (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Telegrams
        - Denikin, Lieut.-Gen. A. to Gen. Franchet d'Esperey, Gen. Milne, Gen. Berthelot and Ambassador Sazonov, typescript transcript (?), February 8, 1919 (Folder 13)
        - Vrangel', Baron P. to M. Girs et al., typescript transcript, November 18, 1921 (Folder 14)
    - Anglo-German Consortium, correspondence and report, typescript, October 29, 1921-December 22, 1922 (Folder 15)
    - Courts of Honor, miscellaneous correspondence, typescript, September 14-November 1, 1921 (Folder 16)
    - Konstantinopol'skii Soiuz Russkikh Ofitserov, correspondence with Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, typescript, Includes printed copy of "Ustav," August 10, December 12, 1921 (Folder 17)
    - Medical institutions of Russian Army abroad, financial report and typescript correspondence, November 8-Dc. 1, 1921 (Folder 18)
    - Poland, reports and correspondence, typescript and handwritten, December 4-26, 1921 (Folder 19)
    - "Radio Moscow," transcripts, typescript, December 7-26, 1921 (Folder 20)
    - Repatriation of Russian military personnel joining units of V.S.IU.R. Includes correspondence with French authorities, typescript and handwritten, April 1919-February 1920 (Folder 21)
    - Russian Army, G.H.Q., circular under signature of Maj.-Gen. P. Kusonskii re non-involvement of Russian Army in politics, typescript, December 11, 1921 (Folder 22)
    - Russkii Zagranichnyi TSerkovnyi Sobor to Russian Army, typescript, December 7, 1921 (Folder 23)
    - Serbia, evacuation of First Cavalry Division from Bizerte, correspondence, typescript, December 16, 1921-December 1, 1922 (Folder 24)
    - Yacht "Lucullus," material re compensation for losses, typescript, October 17-24, 1921 (Folder 25)
    - "Znak otlichiia za trekhletie osvoboditel'noi voiny ," miscellaneous material re creation of order, typescript, November 14-December 24, 1921, 1917-1920 (Folder 26)
    - Reports
      - Author unknown
        - "Svodka svedenii o Krasnom Flote," typescript, November 30, 1921 (Folder 27)
        - "Blizhnii Vostok. Turtsiia. Voennoe Polozhenie," typescript, November 1, 1921 (Folder 28)
      - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., re uprising in Karelia, typescript, December 9, 1921 (Folder 29)
      - Monkevich, Lieut.-Gen., Russian Mission in Berlin, re officers serving in Petliura's army, typescript, June 24, 1919 (Folder 30)
    - Printed matter
      - Bulletins of the Russian Liberation Committee, Nos. 3-5, Also includes correspodence, handwritten and typescript, March 3, 1919, March 10-25, 1919 (Folder 31)
      - "Declaration of Admiral Koltchak's Government,", February 23, 1919 (Folder 32)
      - Russkoe Politicheskoe Soveshchanie v Parizhe, "Obshchii obzor frantsuzkoi pechati,", January-February 1919 (Folder 33)
      - "Union" Agence Télégraphique Russe, No. 39, April 7, 1919 (Folder 34)
      - "Pravila priema na sluzhbu v voiska severnago fronta innostranno-podannykh dobrovol'tsev," Also includes sample contract, schedule of compensation payments in case of injury or death and official correspondence, December 7, 1919-January 3, 1920, December 1, 1919 (Folder 35)
  - (Group I, File 208)
    - Russian Military Representative in Japan
      - Correspondence
        - Diterikhs, Lieut.-Gen. M. and Rear Admiral IU. Stark, transcripts of telegrams, June 3-9, 1922 (Box 91, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 112
        - Girs, M.
          - Bakhmetev, B., Ambassador of the Provisional Government to the U.S., transcript of telegram, October 29, 1920 (Folder 2)
          - Krupenskii, V., Russian Ambassador to Tokyo, September 16-October 21, 1920 (Folder 3)
        - KHadzhiev, KHan Rozak Bek to Maj.-Gen. M. Podtiagin, re mission to KHan of Khiva and Emir of Bukhara, typescript and handwritten, June 15, 1922 (Folder 4)
        - Krupenskii, V., typescript transcripts of telegrams
          - Girs, M., December 22-October 8, 1920 (Folder 5)
          - Struve, P., September 29, 1920 (Folder 6)
        - Miller, Lieut.- Gen. E.
          - Dudorov, Rear-Admiral B., Military and Naval Agent in Tokyo, October 12, 1920-February 21, 1921 (Folder 7)
          - Krupenskii, V., typescript, November 8, 1920-November 41, 1921 (Folder 8)
          - Podtiagin, Maj.-Gen. M., typescript and handwritten, December 23, 1920-July 24, 1922 (Folder 9)
        - Nikolaev, Col. N., Russian Military Agent in the U.S., includes material re Ataman Semenov, typescript and handwritten, February 1921-March 1922 (Folder 10)
        - Podtiagin, Maj.-Gen. M., Russian Military Agent in Japan to Russian Military Agents in Paris Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller and Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen, typescript, 1921-1922 (Folder 11)
      - Intelligence reports, officially classified as secret, typescript
        - 1921
          - "Sovetskaia Sibir'," January (Folder 12)
          - "Svedeniia po Amurskoi Oblasti,", March 3 (Folder 13)
          - "Svedeniia po Dal'ne-Vostochnoi Respubliki,", January 5-March 3 (Folder 14)
          - "Svedeniia po kontr-razvedki,", March 3 (Folder 15)
          - "Svodka dannykh o Sovetskoi Rossii,", February 25 (Folder 16)
          - "Polozhenie Belykh Organizatsiiakh na Dal'nem Vostoke,", March 15 (Folder 17)
          - "Voennoe i ekonomicheskoe polozhenie Sovetskoi Rossii,", April-May (Folder 18)
          - "Svedeniiao Russkoi Armii k nachalu noiabria goda", 1921 (Folder 19)
          - "Svedeniia o Sovetskoi Sibiri i D.V.R.,", November 1 (Folder 20)
        - 1922
          - "Politicheskaia obstanovka v Primor'e,", February 7 (Folder 21)
          - "KHabarovskii raoin,", January 25-February 21 (Folder 22)
          - "Amurskaia Rechnaia Flotiliia,", March 25 (Folder 23)
          - "Raport,", May 29 (Folder 24)
          - "Vnutrennee politicheskoe polozhenie Primoriia,", April 15-May 1 (Folder 25)
          - "Zabaikal'skaia Oblast'. Gruppirovka, sostav i chislennost' voisk,", May 1-15 (Folder 26)
          - "Svodka svedenii o nastrienii chastei armi,", May 7 (Folder 27)
          - "Koreiskoe osvoboditel'noe dvizhenie"; summaries of Soviet newspapers; "Ko vsem chlenam vladivostokskoi organizatsii ross. Kom. P."; "Rabota kommunistov v polose otchuzhdeniia Kit. vost. zh. d."; "Rabota bol'shevikov sredi musul'manskago naseleniia polosy otchuzhdeniia Kit. vost. zh. d."; "Evreiskiia organizatsii gor. Harbina"; "Operativnaia svodka shtaba glavnokomanduiushchago sibirskoi flotiliei,", June 12 (Folder 28)
          - "Vypiska iz dnevnika agenturnykh svedenii"; "Kratkoe opisanie sobytii s 1 po 10 iunia"; "Prichiny perevorota...s 31 maia po 12 iunia"; "Rabota kommunistov...s 1 po 10 iunia,", June 23 (Folder 29)
          - Copies of above sent by Russian Military Agent in Paris to M. Girs et al., July 7-27 (Folder 30)
        - Karpenko, Col. N., Representative of Ataman Semenov in Japan, "Zapiska,", undated (Folder 31)
          Available on microfilm reel 113
        - Kmit, Michman, "Nachal'niku shtaba komanduiushchago sibirskoi flotiliei," re situation in Amur Region, undated (Folder 32)
        - Staryi Kappelevets (pseud.), "Neskol'ko slov o 'Semenovskoi orientatsii',", undated (Folder 33)
      - Printed matter
        - Summaries of newspaper articles
          - Tokio Asakhi Simbun, typescript, February 7-8, 1921 (Folder 34)
          - Zabaikal'skaia Nov', interview with Gen. Bangerskii, typescript, August 29, 1921 (Folder 35)
        - Leaflets
          - "Ot Vremennago Priamurskago Pravitel'stva," signed S. Merkulov, undated (Folder 36)
          - "Za chto my boremsia s bol'shevikami?,", undated (Folder 37)
          - "Ob"iavlenie Komanduiushchago Sibirskoi Flotiliei zhiteliam selenii po poberezh'iu Ussuriiskago zaliva," signed Kontr-Admiral Stark, 1922 (Folder 38)
          - "Biulleten' Soveta upolnomochennykh organizatsii Avtonomnoi Sibiri," No. 1, June 2, 1922 (Folder 39)
          - "Vashe Prevoskhoditel'stvo...Maioru V.M. Molchanovu," signed Kontr-Admiral Stark, June 3, 1922 (Folder 40)
          - "Ukaz No. 148 vremennago priamurskago pravitel'stva," signed S. Merkulov, June 4, 1922 (Folder 41)
          - "Prikaz komanduiushchago vsemi vooruzhennymi silami Vr. Priamurskago Pravitel'stva,", June 5, 1922 (Folder 42)
  - (Group I, File 209)
    - Miscellaneous material, including correspondence re missing persons, military service records, discharge papers and other documentation re officers formerly serving in Russian Expeditionary Corps in France, typescript and handwritten, 1920-1921 (Box 92, Folder 1-3)
  - (Group I, File 210)
    - Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta
      - Glavnoe Upravlenie Rossiiskago Obshchestva Krasnago Kresta
        - Correspondence
          - General, typescript, January 1921-March 1922 (Box 92, Folder 4)
          - Office, mostly between B. Ivanitskii, chairman of G.U.R.O.K.K. and Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller re relations between R.O.K.K. and Voenno-Sanitarnoe Vedomstvo, typescript, November 1921-May 1922 (Folder 5)
        - Financial records, typescript, February 15, 1921 (Folder 6)
        - List of representatives abroad, typescript, August 18, 1920 (Folder 7)
        - Minutes of meetings, mimeograph, August 6-August 18, 1921 (Folder 8)
        - Report of B. Ivanitskii re visit to Serbia, Bulgaria and Turkey, typescript, July 1922 (Folder 9)
      - Regional offices
        - Austria. Miscellaneous material, including financial records, typescript, 7, 1922, February 15, 1921-February 22 (Folder 10)
        - Bulgaria. Reports: re conditions in "Invalidnyi dom," typescript, undated; negotiations with representatives of League of Nations, American Red Cross and A.R.A. re resettlement of invalid servicemen in Bulgaria, typescript, August 6, 1922 (Folder 11)
        - China and Japan. Transcripts of telegrams, November 28, 1920-January 29, 1921 (Folder 12)
        - Constantinople. Transcripts of telegrams, August 15-November 29, 1920 (Folder 13)
        - Czechoslovakia. Correspondence, typescript (?), January 27-31, 1921 (Folder 14)
        - Denmark. Miscellaneous material, typescript and handwritten, September 25-October 3, 1921 (Folder 15)
        - Estonia. Report re refugees from army of Lieut.-Gen. N. IUdenich, typescript, August 27-December 15, 1920 (Folder 16)
        - Finland. Correspondence, typescript, September 18-November 11, 1921 (Folder 17)